# Hiroko Yamaji Software Engineer (React.js)

hiroko@hirokoymj.com +1-310-878-4588 Green Card holder

**Skills** 

- React.js
- React Hooks
- Redux/Redux Toolkit
- TypeScript
- JavaScript
- Apollo Server/Client
- GraphQL
- Material UI
- Chart.js
- Lodash
- Node.js
- MongoDB
- Mongoose
- HTML5/CSS3/Sass
- Responsive Web Design
- Bootstrap 4
- Git (branch, rebase, stash)
- GitLab

### Software

- Visual Studio Code
- Heroku
- Photoshop CC
- Figma
- Slack/Google Meet

## **APIs**

- Google Map API
- Open Weather API
- Postman Covid-19 API

## Languages

- Japanese
- English

#### **US Status**

Green card holder

I am a Software Engineer who lived in Los Angeles for 16 years and specialize in building responsive web applications. My strongest skill is React.js with 3 years of experience. I currently live in Tokyo, Japan and will be returning to the US in June 2022. I am a green card holder and looking for a new job in Los Angeles and Seattle.

**FRONT-END (React + TypeScript)**: https://www.hirokoymj.com **BACK-END (GraphQL)**: https://hirokoymj-backend.herokuapp.com/ **GitHub:** https://github.com/hirokoymj/hiroko-frontend

## Work Experience

Asurion Japan

May 2021 – January 2022

Tokyo, Japan (Contractor/ Full remote)

Frontend Engineer – React.js + TypeScript (Apollo client, GraphQL, Git) Worked with offshore members in India from Tokyo. Fixed defects and added new features in React applications. Testing the code using cypress.

HyreCar Inc.

January 2019 - December 2020

Los Angeles, CA 90071

Software Engineer – React.js (Apollo Client, Material UI, GraphQL, Git)

Refactoring a React application to fix deeply nested components structure. The new architecture was used React hooks, Redux-Form and Material UI. All pages were coded from scratch.

Beachbody.com

December 2017 – September 2018

Santa Monica, CA 90404

Frontend Engineer - React.js (JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Gulp.js)

Built an image slider and carousel with React.js in Beachbody homepage.

Strategic Partners Inc.

December 2016 – June 2017

Chatsworth, CA 91311

Frontend Engineer (React, Weather API, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, SASS)

Build React components to display a local weather info with Weather API.

Teleflora.com

October 2009 – October 2016

Los Angeles, CA, 90064

Frontend Developer (JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Gulp.js, Bootstrap3)

Building responsive landing pages for the Teleflora e-commerce site.

MC Squared

September 2006 – November 2007

Los Angeles, CA 90071

Web Developer (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, MySQL)

Sony Electronics Inc. (Contractor)

July 2005 – July 2006

Santa Monica, CA 90404

Web Developer (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Java, JSP, MySQL, Apache)

Education	
Santa Monica College  Certificate of Interactive Media	February 2004 - June 2005
Yamawaki Gakuten Junior College Tokyo, Japan Associate of Arts in Food Science	April 1989 – March 1991

References available upon request.